Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Gertrude Stein, 1894-1947; Series I; 39; (94 boxes)
  - BOUND VOLUMES
    - Volume 9, ca. 1908-12 (Box 88, Folder 1695)
      Lederman. p. 71, corrected A Painter. p. 75, corrected Elise Surville. p. 78, corrected Four Dishonest Ones. Told by a Description of what They do. p. 83 corrected A Kind of Women. p. 91, corrected A Family. p. 106, corrected
    - Volume 10, ca. 1908-12 (Box 88, Folder 1696)
      Includes: Ada p. 1, corrected Julia Marlowe p. 6 Frost p. 9 Purmann p. 15, corrected Russell p. 19, corrected
      Pach p. 22, corrected Chalfin p. 25, corrected Harriet [Fear] p. 28 Hessel p. 36 Roché p. 39, corrected
      Constance Fletcher [Pt. 1] p. 43 Harriet p. 47, corrected [Storyette] Matisse p. 51 Play[ing] p. 52 Rue de Rennes p. 55, corrected
      Pleasant [Bon Marche] Weather p. 58, corrected Mi Careme p. 62, corrected [Flirting at the] Bon Marche p. 70, corrected [Aux] Galeries Lafayette p. 75, Miss Furr & Miss Skeene p. 80, corrected
    - Volume 11, ca. 1910-13 (Box 89, Folder 1697)
      Includes: Tender Buttons. p. 1, consisting of: Rooms p. 1, corrected; Objects. p. 25, corrected; and Food p. 52, corrected
      Portrait of Mabel Dodge at the Villa Curiona. p. 89 A Portrait of One. [Henry Phelan Gibb] p. 95 Portrait of Constance Fletcher. p. 97
      Scenes. Actions and Dispositions of Relations and Positions. p. 109, corrected Publishers, the Portrait Gallery And the Manuscripts and the British Museum. p. 138, corrected
      Portrait of F. B. p. 146, corrected Portrait of Prince B. D. p. 150, corrected England. p. 157, corrected What Happened. A Play in Five Acts. by Gertrude Stein. p. 174, corrected
      One. (Van Vechten.) p. 182, Article. p. 185, corrected White Wines. Three Acts. I. Altogether 2. Witnesses. 3. House to House. (Five Women.) p. 188, corrected Braque. p. 195, corrected
      IIIIIIIIII. p. 202 A Play. Old and Old., consisting of: 1. Conditions.; 2. Treatment; 3. Collecting Poles.; 4. Invite.; 5. A Told High Floors, Colossal, Swell, Red. 6. Wodos., 7. Grass Trees., and 8. Cut Indians. p. 212, corrected
      Susie Asado. p. 227 Mrs. Thursbey. p. 229, A Curtain Raiser. p. 231 Miguel. (Collusion.) Guimpe. Candle. p. 233 Simons. A Bouquet. (necessary) p. 244
      In General. p. 263 Thank You. p. 265 A Sweet Tail. p. 267, corrected Carnage. p. 273, corrected Yet Dish. p. 277, corrected Americans. p. 288, corrected In. p. 297, corrected
    - Volume 12, ca. 1913-13 (Box 89, Folder 1698)
      Includes: In the Grass. On Spain. p. 1, corrected Guillaume. p. 14 Carry. p. 16 France. p. 18, corrected
      Go in Green. p. 32 Simon. p. 34 Bee Time Vine. p. 39 Irma. p. 42 A lide Close. The Story of a Spanish Morrison. p. 44
      Mrs. Edwardes. p. 46, corrected Preciosilla. p. 48 Sacred Emily. p. 51, corrected Meal One. p. 65, corrected Emp Lace. p. 79, corrected
      Series. p. 112, corrected Tillie. p. 119 Curtain Let Us. p. 121, corrected Dates. p. 124
      Four. p. 129, consisting of: Fine. p. 130; Of. p. 131; Brother p. [131bis]; and Firm p. 132
      Finished One. p. 133, corrected Oval. p. 137, corrected One or Two. I've Finished. p. 193, Crete. p. 195 In One. p. 198,
      Wear. p. 200 Gentle Julia. p. 203 Printed Lace. p. 205, corrected At. p. 211 New Happiness. p. 217, corrected
      Mrs. Whitehead. p. 235, corrected Lockeridge. p. 239 Mrs. Emerson. p. 242, corrected Tubene. p. 253 Bird Jet. p. 255 One Sentence. p. 257, corrected
    - Volume 13, ca. 1915 (Box 89, Folder 1699)
      Includes: Not Sightly. (A Play.) p. 1, corrected Pink Melon Joy. p. 19, corrected Johhny Grey. p. 56, corrected Study Nature. p. 68 Possessive Case. p. 71, corrected
      No. p. 137, corrected M. Vollard et Cezanne p. 184, When We Went Away. p. 188 Farragut. or A Husband's Recompense. p. 190 How Could They Marry Her. p. 206, corrected
      If You Had Three Husbands. p. 228, corrected This One Is Serious. p. 246, corrected He Didn't Light the Light. p. 252, corrected David Daisy and Appolonia. p. 256
      Independent Embroidery. p. 258, corrected I Have No Title to be Successful. p. 263, corrected He Said It. Monologue. p. 268 corrected
    - Volume 14, ca. 1916 (Box 90, Folder 1700)
      Includes: In the Country Entirely. A Play in Letters p. 1, corrected What Does Cook Want To Do. p. 16 It Was an Accident. p. 19 Mr. Miranda and William. p. 21
      Henry and I. p. 23 We Have Eaten Heartily and We Were Alarmed. p. 25 Letters and Parcels and Wool. p. 30, corrected Water Pipe. p. 46 Ladies' Voices. Curtain Raiser. p. 51 Every Afternoon. A Dialogue. p. 54, corrected
      Advertisements. p. 62, corrected, consisting of: I Am Not Patient, To Open, Do Let us Be Faithful and True, A Grape Cure, Battle, Fastening Tube Roses, They Do it Better than I Do, It Is a Natural Thing, Loud Letters, Pleasures in Sincere Wishes, An Exhibition, The Boat, Threadneedle Street, Present, and Evian Water
      Do Let Us Go Away. A Play. p. 71, corrected Let Us Be Easily Careful. p. 86, corrected Bonne Annee. A Play. p. 92, corrected Captain William Edwards. p. 95, corrected
      Polybe Silent. p. 98, corrected Please Do Not Suffer. (A Play.) p. 102, corrected A Very Good House. p. 109 Turkey and Bones and Eating and We Liked It. A Play. p. 114, corrected
      I Often Think About An Other. p. 132, corrected A Collection. p. 136 My Dear Miss Carey. A Story p. 137 Polybe in Port. A Curtain Raiser. p. 140 Spanish Chattings. p. 141 They Came Together. p. 142 Wild Flowers. p. 143 Will They Crush Germany. p. 144
      I Must Try to Write the History of Belmonte. p. 145, corrected Universe or Hand-Reading. p. 151, corrected Mallorcan Stories. p. 157 Look At Us. p. 159, corrected Mexico. A Play. p. 172, corrected
      Decorations. p. 206, corrected A Poem About Walberg. p. 210 All Sunday. p. 212, corrected I Like it to be a Play. ( A Play.) p. 262 corrected Captain Walter Arnold. A Play. p. 267
    - Volume 15, ca. 1917-20 (Box 90, Folder 1701)
      Includes: Lifting Belly. p. 1, corrected Miss Crutwell. p. 71 corrected A King or Something. The Public is Invited To Dance. p. 104 Marry Nettie. Alright make it a series and call it Marry Nettie. p. 119, corrected
      Counting Her Dresses. A Play. p. 130 Have They Attcked Mary. He giggled. (A Political Satire.) p. 143 An Exercise in Analysis. A Play. p. 151, corrected I Can Feel the Beauty. p. 172, corrected
      Will We See Them Again. p. 186 Why Can Kipling Speak. p. 189 (Also includes: One Has Not Lost One's Marguerite. p. 191 Why Win Wings. p. 192, In Their Play. p. 193
      Can You Behave Better. p. 194 What Is the Name of a Ring. p. 195 In the Middle of a Day. p. 196 Do You Like Your Suit. p. 197 The Ford. p. 198
      Call It a Table. p. 199 Third Day not Thirsty. p. 200 Can Call Us. p. 201 Can You See the Name. p. 202 (Also includes: Exceptional Conduct. p. 205)
      Light Butter. p. 206 James is Nervous. p. 207 In This Shape Wood. p. 208 Mirror. p. 209 Can You Speak. p. 210 Red Faces. p. 211 Can You Sit in a Tree. p. 212
      Selected Poems. p. 213, corrected Amaryllis or the Prettiest of Legs. p. 214 An Incident p. 214 What is This. p. 214 A Lesson for Baby. p. 215
      A Radical Expert. p. 215 America. p. 216 Your Own. p. 216 Let Us Talk About Waxing. p. 217 In This Way, Kissing. p. 217 Can You Imitate Disaster. p. 218,
      In the Same Poem. p. 218 An Elegant Escape. p. 218 Can You Climb in Little Things. p. 218 We Cannot. p. 219 Why Cannot you Speak in Pieces. p. 219 Making Sense. p. 219
      Barrels. p. 223 Also includes: Rich In the City. p. 226 Monday and Tuesday. A Play. p. 227, corrected
      The Present. p. 230 (Also includes: Italy, The Liberty Loan, Sacred Fountain of Bellows, Say It Again, Postal Cards, J. R., Accents in Alsace. A reasonable tragedy. and Scene Mulhouse p. 234, corrected)
      Our Aid. p. 243, The Meaning of the Bird. p. 244 A Deserter. p. 245 Relief Work in France. p. 246, consisting of: The Advance; Monday and Tuesday; The Right Spirit; and Victory, Again
      A Poetical Plea. p. 249 corrected Scenes from the Door. p. 250 Prim Roses. p. 253 Then Steal. p. 254 A Patriotic Leading. p. 255 (Also Includes: [White Wings.] p. 257)
      I Expressed My Opinion. p. 257 Animated. p. 257 Won. p. 258 Left Poem. p. 259 The Great American Army. p. 260
      The Work. p. 262, corrected Work Again. p. 271, corrected Tourty or Tourtebattre. A Story of the Great War. p. 282 [Old Dogs.] p. 288 [Kicking.] p. 289
      Ireland. p. 290, corrected (Also includes: [Would.] p. 293) A Movie. p. 294 Polish. p. 298 The Revery of the Zionist. p. 300, corrected
      A League. p. 302 More League. p. 303 Events. p. 304 A Hymn. p. 305 The Psychology of Nations or What are you looking at. p. 306,
      Daughter. p. 310 Next. Life and Letters of Marcel Duchamp. p. 311, corrected Names of Flowers. p. 313 Rich and Poor in English. to subscribe in French and other latin languages. p. 314
      Photographs. p. 318 corrected Scenery. p. 323, corrected Coal and Wood. p. 325, corrected Land of Nations (sub-title) And Ask Asia. p. 336 [Develop Spanish.] p. 339 Land Rising. p. 340
    - Volume 16, ca. 1920-22 (Box 90, Folder 1702)
      Includes: A Circular Play. A Play in Circles. p. 1, corrected Vacation in Brittany. p. 18, corrected Woodrow Wilson. p. 20, corrected B. B. or The Birthplace of Bonnes. p. 31, corrected
      Moral Tales of 1920 and 1921. p. 37, corrected Nest of Dishes. p. 53, corrected Emily Chadbourne. p. 66, corrected Not a Hole. p. 68, corrected Curtains Dream. p. 69, corrected
      Dinner. p. 70, corrected Courting. p. 71 Kites. p. 72 Readings. p. 73 Separated. p. 74
      Attacks. p. 75 Jokes for Jessie. p. 76 Dolphin. p. 77 Little Pillows. p. 78 Singing to a Musician. p. 79, corrected
      Finish Constance. p. 85 A Sonatina Followed by Another. by Gertrude Stein. Dedicated by request to D. D. p. 86, corrected [No. 2] p. 101, corrected
      Currents. p. 123, corrected Mary. p. 127 Capture Splinters. p. 128 A Little Cream. p. 130 Think Again. p. 131
      Read a New Currant. p. 132 To-day We Have a Vacation. p. 133 Sonnets that Please. p. 134, corrected Reread Another. A Play. To be played indoors or out. I wish to be a school. p. 136, corrected
      Objects Lie on a Table. A Play. p. 146, corrected Saints and Singing. Called Saints and Singing as a Protest against Demi virgins p. 155, corrected
      As Fine As Melanctha p. 177, corrected I Feel a Really Anxious Moment Coming p. 196 corrected Mildred's Thoughts p. 201, corrected
    - Volume 17, ca. 1922-23 (Box 90, Folder 1703)
      Includes: Didn't Nellie and Lily Love You. p. 1, corrected American Biography and Why Waste It. p. 42 An Instant Answer or A Hundred Prominent Men. p. 51
      Jo Davidson. p. 69 A Singular Addition. A Sequal to An Instant Answer or One Prominent Men. p. 72, corrected Talks to Saints. or Stories of Saint Remy. p. 84, corrected
      A Saint in Seven. p. 96, corrected Lend a Hand or Four Religions. p. 103, corrected Why Are There Whites to Console. A History in Three Parts. p. 139
      A Valentine. p. 165, corrected Prudence Caution and Foresight. A Story of Avignon. p. 171, corrected If He Thinks. A Novelette of Desertion. p. 176, corrected Lily Life. p. 182
      Procession. p. 184 For Ten. 1. Very Prettily 2. Chapter 2. 3. Did she read. 4. He knows. p. 189 Praises. p. 191 Harold Loeb. p. 193
      Fourteen Anonymous Portraits. p. 194, corrected Cezanne. p. 197 An Indian Boy. p. 198, corrected Precepts. p. 201 A List. p. 204, corrected
      Capital Capitals. p. 224, corrected Jonas Julian Caesar and Samuel. p. 237, corrected Elucidation. p. 243, corrected Yes you do. p. 258
      A Village. Are You Ready Yet Not Yet. A Play in Four Acts. p. 265 Practice or Oratory. p. 272
    - Volume 18, ca. 1923-24 (Box 91, Folder 1704)
      Includes: Subject-Cases The Background of a Detective Story p. 1, corrected Am I To Go or I'll Say So. p. 38, corrected He and They, Hemmingway. p. 52 A Book by Gertrude Stein Concluding with As a Wife Had a Cow With Coloured Illustrations by Juan Gris p. 54 As a Wife Has a Cow A Love Story p. 63, corrected
      Van or Twenty Years After A Second Portrait of Carl Van Vechten. By Gertrude Stein. p. 67, corrected Are There Arithmetics. p. 70, corrected New. p. 75, If I Told Him. A Completed Portrait of Picasso p. 83
      Geography. p. 88, corrected As Eighty or Numbered from One to Eighty A Disputation p. 94, corrected Are There Six or Another Question. p. 101
      Studies in Conversation p. 103, corrected Equally So A Description of All the Incidents Which I Have Observed in Travelling and on my Return p. 108, corrected
      Wherein the South Differs from the North p. 128 corrected Birthday Book. p. 149, corrected In Which House Did He Live. p. 183, corrected Wherein Iowa Differs from Kansas and Indiana. p. 191, corrected
      Elected Again p. 197, corrected Difference Between the Inhabitants of France and the Inhabitants of the United States of America. p. 200 Made a Mile Away. p. 209, corrected Mildred Aldrich Saturday p. 223, corrected
      And So. To Change So. (A Fantasy on Three Careers) p. 235, corrected Birth and Marriage. p. 243, corrected Dahomy or As Soft a Noise A Serial p. 274, corrected Pictures of Juan Gris. p. 295,
      The Brazilian Admiral's Son. p. 298, corrected Emmet Addis the Doughboy A Pastoral p. 308, corrected
    - Volume 19, ca. 1924-26 (Box 91, Folder 1705)
      Includes: A Description of the Fifteenth of November (A Portrait of T.S. Eliot) p. 1 Like That (A Comedy) p. 6, corrected Coloured As Colours a Gift p. 16, corrected
      Descriptions of Literature p. 21, Which One Will p. 25, corrected To Call It a Day p. 30, corrected Man Ray p. 41 Near East or Chicago p. 44,
      After at Once p. 53, corrected A History or Having a Great Many Times Not Continued to be Friends p. 65, corrected Early and Late p. 118 Sitwell Edith Sitwell p. 127
      On War (or More) p. 130, corrected Useful Knowledge Among Negroes p. 159 Business in Baltimore. p. 162, corrected A Third p. 177, corrected Lipschitz p. 212
      Jean Cocteau p. 213 An Address Given in Cambridge and Oxford June 1926 p. 218, corrected Edith Sitwell and her Brother the Sitwells And Also to Osbert Sitwell p. 233, corrected
      Allen p. 243 An Acquaintance with Description p. 245, corrected Pavlik Tchelitchef or Adrian Arthur p. 289
    - Volume 20, ca. 1925 (Box 91, Folder 1706)
      Includes: A Novel of Thank You, corrected
  - CARNETS
    - "Literature": notes on status of writings submitted to publishers [with one loose leaf laid in], [1920] (Box 92, Folder 1707)
    - Notes for writings: Pictures of Juan Gris; Notes between GS and ABT; notes; sketches, [1921] (Box 92, Folder 1708)
    - Notes for writings: If I told him; notes between GS and ABT, addresses, [1923] (Box 92, Folder 1709)
    - Notes for writings: Geography, AND If I told him; notes between GS and ABT; addresses; note about purchasing carnets, [1923] (Box 92, Folder 1710)
    - Notes for writings: Geography, AND As eighty; draft of letter to Sherwood Anderson; notes between GS and ABT, [1923] (Box 92, Folder 1711)
    - Notes for writings: Equally so; draft of letter to Mr. Vogel of Vogue; notes between GS and ABT, addresses, calculations, [1923 Dec] (Box 92, Folder 1712)
    - Notes for writings; The Brazilian admiral's son, Birth and Marriage, AND Emmet Addis the doughboy. A pastoral, draft of letter to Ford Madox Ford; notes between GS and ABT; addresses; notes, [1924] (Box 92, Folder 1713)
    - Notes for writings: War [or more], Early and late, A Novel of Thank You, After at once, AND [title only for play, How to Write or Everything Away]; draft of letter to Kristians Tonny; notes between GS and ABT; addresses [includes one leaf laid in], [1924-25] (Box 92, Folder 1714)
    - Notes for writings; A Third, AND A Novel of Thank you; sketch; notes, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1715)
    - Notes for writings: Phenomena of Nature, AND Business in Baltimore; notes between GS and ABT; addresses, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1716)
    - Notes for writings: War, Early and late, A Novel of Thank You, AND After at Once; notes between GS and ABT; addresses, list of book titles, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1717)
    - Notes for writings: Early and late, War, AND A Novel of Thank You; notes between GS and ABT, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1718)
    - Notes for writings: Phenomena of Nature, A Novel of Thank You, AND A third; notes between GS and ABT, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1719)
    - Notes for writings; A Novel of Thank You, Phenomena of nature, Business in Baltimore, AND a review of Troubadour by Alfred Kreymborg; notes between GS and ABT, [1925] (Box 92, Folder 1720)
    - Notes for writings: Phenomena of Nature, A Novel of Thank You, AND a third; Notes between GS and ABT; sketches; addresses; [note re: Louise Taylor?], [1925 Aug] (Box 92, Folder 1721)
    - Notes for writings: A Novel of Thank You, AND Phenomena of Nature; notes between GS and ABT; addresses, [1925-26] (Box 92, Folder 1722)
    - Notes between GS and ABT, Notes for writings: Edith Sitwell and her brothers the Sitwells and also To Osbert Sitwell and to S. Sitwell, An Acquaintance with description, A Novel of Thank You, AND A third; autobiographical sketch by GS; map; house plans; addresses, [1926] (Box 92, Folder 1723)
    - Drafts of letters: to Joseph Brewer, to Madame Pierlot, to Georges Maratier, to Eugène Jolas, and to Clarence Andrews, [1928] (Box 92, Folder 1724)
    - Notes for writings: Sentences, Five words in a line, Basket, AND Film: Deux soeurs qui ne sont pas soeurs; draft of letter: to Laura (Riding) Jackson: addresses; plan for Plain Edition; shopping list, [1928] (Box 92, Folder 1725)
    - Notes for writings: How to Write - Arthur a grammar, AND Their wills. A bouquet; drafts of letters: [to Radcliffe College?], [to Bernard Faÿ?], bnd re: Elliot Paul; notes between GS and ABT; lists of titles, [1928] (Box 92, Folder 1726)
    - Notes for writings: Sentences; notes re: Pavel Tchelitchew, Bernard Faÿ, and the Four Seas Company; notes between GS and ABT; addresses, [1928-29] (Box 93, Folder 1727)
    - Notes for writings: Basketing [i.e. Saving the Sentence], AND More Grammar [Genia Berman], draft of letter to Bob Brown; notes, sketches [one loose leaf], [1929] (Box 93, Folder 1728)
    - Notes for writings: Title Subtitle, Parlor, statement on Bravig Imbs for the Guggenheim Foundation, Sentences and Paragraphs, Genuine Creative Ability, AND A Grammarian; drafts of letter to Henry Horwood; notes on Plain Edition; addresses, [1929-30] (Box 93, Folder 1729)
    - Notes for writings: Before the flowers of friendship faded friendship faded, AND Think with a minute; draft of letter to Mary Garden, notes, addresses, [1930] (Box 93, Folder 1730)
    - Notes for writings: How to Write - More Grammar for a sentence; notes; lists, [1930] (Box 93, Folder 1731)
    - Notes for writings: Phenomena of Nature, A Third, A Novel of Thank you, AND Jean Cocteau [portrait]; notes between GS and ABT; addresses (Box 93, Folder 1732)
    - Notes for writings: A third, Phenomena of Nature, AND A Novel of Thank You; notes (Box 93, Folder 1733)
    - Notes for writings: A Novel of Thank You; notes between GS and ABT (Box 93, Folder 1734)
    - Notes for writings: A third, Phenomena of Nature, AND A Novel of Thank You, drafts of letters: to Mr. [William?] Bird, and Monsieur Maurice; drafts of inscriptions [to Carl, to Sherwood, to Jane and to Edith Sitwell; notes between GS and ABT, addresses (Box 93, Folder 1735)
    - Notes for writings, drafts of letters [to "Harriet", "G-----" (re: American Fund for the French Wounded)] (Box 93, Folder 1736)
    - Notes for writings: Paisieu A play, AND Arthur a Grammar; drafts of letters: to Madame Pierlot, to Réné Crevel, to Clarence Andrews, and to unidentified [re: the Four Seas Company]; addresses (Box 93, Folder 1737)
    - Notes for writings: Are you ready yet not yet, An Elucidation, AND a Village; notes between GS and ABT (Box 93, Folder 1738)
    - Drafts of letters: to Mrs. Mitchell, to Dr. L----, and to unidentified; notes for writings: A Deserter, Looks, and Little kissing (Box 93, Folder 1739)
    - Notes for writings: A Sister's revenge; notes between GS and ABT (Box 93, Folder 1740)
    - Notes for writings: An Acquaintance with Description, AND Duchesse de Rohan, notes between GS and ABT; addresses; floorplans; sketches (Box 93, Folder 1741)
    - Notes for writings: Like that, Man Ray, In half, In English, AND To call it a day; drafts of letters: to Editor of the Transatlantic Review, and to Emmet Addis; titles for a book with Juan Gris; addresses; sketch; notes (Box 93, Folder 1742)
    - Notes for writings: War; notes between GS and ABT (Box 93, Folder 1743)
    - Notes for writings; notes between GS and ABT (Box 93, Folder 1744)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Anderson, Sherwood
      - "The Work of Gertrude Stein" [introduction to Geography and Plays], typescript carbon, corrected (Box 94, Folder 1745)
    - Baschet, Réné
      - "Cubisme," page proof, 1936 (Box 94, Folder 1746)
    - [Crapo, Mary Morley?]
      - "34 Seniors Reacting: An Opera," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1747)
    - Genin, Paul
      - "Mon Livre de Pourquoi", typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1748)
    - Hemingway, Ernest
      - "The Age Demanded," typescript carbon (Box 94, Folder 1749)
      - "Quick Assets and Dead," typescript, corrected (Box 94, Folder 1750)
      - [Excerpts of his works with military comments on the suitability of his work for enlisted men], 1945 (Box 94, Folder 1751)
    - McCollum, Miriam
      - Holograph notes beginning "some x is y", n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1752)
    - [Schwab, Francey?]
      - [Notebook with story about "Sainte Blondie"] (Box 94, Folder 1753)
    - [Sorter, F.?]
      - "The Mirror of the English," printed version, France-Grande Bretagne, inscribed to Gertrude Stein, 1945 Apr (Box 94, Folder 1754)
    - Walton, William
      - "One Man's Education", typescript carbon, 1945 Oct 1 (Box 94, Folder 1755)
    - Unidentified
      - "L'Amerique découvre Gertrude Stein," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1756)
      - [Cahier with poems in French], n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1757)
      - "Frontière" [film outline], typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1758)
      - [Testimonial to Raymond Schwab], typescript and holograph (Box 94, Folder 1759)
      - "Voisinage avec Gertrude Stein," typescript, ca. 1940 (Box 94, Folder 1760)
- Gertrude Stein Correspondence, 1893-1946; Series II; 16.25; (40 boxes)
  Series II, Correspondence, is divided into subseries, all of which are arranged by name.
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1925-46, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1761)
    - [Aarnestad?], Elling, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1762)
      GS: drafts of responses
    - Abbott, Moreton Graves, 1938, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1763)
    - Abdy, Diana, Lady, 1933-[37], n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1764)
    - Abdy, Robert, Sir, 1932-45, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1765)
    - Abélard, Amelie, 1932 Jan 5 (Box 95, Folder 1766)
    - Abercrombie, Gertrude, 1936 (Box 95, Folder 1767)
    - Acosta, Mercedes de, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1768)
    - Activités, 1933 Mar (Box 95, Folder 1769)
      GS: draft of response
    - Acton, Arthur, 1912, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1770)
    - Acton, Harold, 1926-1945 (Box 95, Folder 1771)
    - Adamov, Ar, 1928, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1772)
    - Adams, Clifford, 1945-46 (Box 95, Folder 1773)
    - Addis, Emmet, 1929, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1774)
      See: Series I., Writings,, Carnets - n.d., Box 93, folder 1742 for GS: draft of letter
    - Addis, Louise Hayden, [1934?], n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1775)
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 95, Folder 1776)
    - Adler, Rose, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1777)
    - Agelaste, M., 1934 (Box 95, Folder 1778)